

# ARCADIY KULCHINSKIY FULL-STACK DESIGNER

**PORTFOLIO** 

behance.com/kulchinskiy

# **BASIC INFORMATION**

**BIRTH DATE** 

March 18, 1989

NATIONALITY

Portuguese

**RESIDENCE** 

Lisbon Area, Portugal

**SPOKEN LANGUAGE** 

English (B2), Portuguese (Native), Russian (Native)

### **EXPERTISE RECAP**

Digital Product Design, User Experience Reseach, UI Design, Brand Design, Instructional Design, Motion Design, VFX, Video Production, Front-end Development, Teaching Experience, Managing Experience, Coordinating Experience

### **CONTACTS**

**EMAIL** 

arcadiy.kulchinskiy@gmail.com

PHONE NUMBER / WHATSAPP

+351 919 731 902

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/akulchinskiy

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a **Product, UX** and **UI Designer, Digital Media Creator (Video, VFX and Motion Design), Instructional Designer** and **Front-end Developer,** with over 13 years of proven experience. I have been coordinating medium-large scale digital projects, managing teams of designers and developers, and teaching in schools and universities. Currently I work at Nearshore Portugal as the consultant for VOITH - a German multinational corporation in the mechanical engineering sector, as well as the automation and IoT business, creating a digital platform for large industries across the world.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

VOITH GMBH & CO / NEARSHORE PORTUGAL

SR. PRODUCT DESIGNER | TECHNICAL COORDINATOR | FRONT-END DEVELOPER April 2021 - Present, Lisbon, PT - Munich, DE

UX DESIGNER I UI DESIGNER

December 2020 - April 2021, Lisbon, PT - Munich, DE

INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER | DIGITAL MEDIA DESIGNER (VIDEO AND MOTION) | DIGITAL DESIGNER May 2019 - December 2020, Lisbon, PT - Munich, DE

#### PORTUGUESE PSYCHOLOGISTS ASSOCIATION

Brand Designer | Full Stack Designer | Front-end Developer March 2017 - April 2019, Lisbon, PT

#### MAAT MUSEUM / EDP FOUNDATION

BRAND DESIGNER I UX DESIGNER I VISUAL DESIGNER (DIGITAL AND EDITORIAL) March 2016 - March 2017, Lisbon, PT

JORNAL I / SOJORMEDIA CAPITAL

SENIOR MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER I VIDEO REPORTER I UI DESIGNER (WEB, STV AND APP)

September 2012 - March 2014, Lisbon, PT

DIGITAL MARKETING MANAGER

August 2013 - March 2014, Lisbon, PT

**VORTAL S.A.** 

UI AND GRAPHIC DESIGNER

August 2010 - December 2010, Lisbon, PT

THE EDGE

UI, GRAPHIC DESIGNER, DIGITAL MEDIA DESIGNER (TRAINEE)

January 2009 - April 2009, Lisbon, PT

## **ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE**

• UNIVERSIDADE LUSÍADA DE LISBOA - TEACHER OF DESIGN PRINCIPLES (LLP)

April 2014 - November 2014, Lisbon, PT

FCSH - UNIVERSIDADE NOVA DE LISBOA - DISSERTATION RESEARCH

September 2013 - January 2015, Lisbon, PT

LX SCHOOL - TEACHER OF INTERACTION DESIGN

January 2011 - August 2011, Lisbon, PT

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

FOOD BANK AGAINST HUNGER - FOOD COLLECTING 2009, Lisbon, PT

INSTITUTO PORTUGUES DA JUVENTUDE - FOREST GUARD 2008, Lisbon, PT

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- "AFTER 100 YEARS, WHAT'S LEFT OF RUSSIAN REVOLUTION?" SAP024 2018, Article
- \*SEMIOTIC PERSUASION AND PROPAGANDA" FCSH, UNIVERSIDADE NOVA DE LISBOA 2015, Dissertation
- "DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION AND POST-HUMANISM" FCSH, UNIVERSIDADE NOVA DE LISBOA 2015, Article
- "WHAT IS THE SOUND OF PORTUGAL?" NOTÍCIAS MAGAZINE 2012, Article

#### **MEMBERSHIP**

INTELECTUAL CAPITAL ACREDITATION Associate, 2015 - Present

NATIONAL ASSOCIATION FOR ENTERPENTEURS Associate, 2010 - 2013

# REFERENCES / RECOMMENTATIONS



**OSVALDO SANTOS** PhD, University of Lisbon



**PEDRO GADANHO**General Director, MAAT museum



**HERMENEGILDO BORGES** PhD, Universidade Nova de Lisboa



**MARCELIN LEWINSKI** PhD, Universidade Nova de Lisboa



MARIA ANTÓNIA COUTINHO PhD, Universidade Nova de Lisboa



**ÁLVARO CIDRAIS**PhD, Universidade Lusíada de Lisboa



TERESA FERNANDES Marketing Director, Vortal S.A.

#### **EDUCATION IN MAJOR COURSES**

FCSH - NOVA UNIVERSITY OF LISBON
MASTER DEGREE - COMMUNICATION SCIENCES

Lisbon, PT, Graduated of 2015

Dissertation research entitled "Semiotic Persuasion and Propaganda", where the empirical part focused on a semiotic and rhetorics analysis used in a perspectivism theory for social engineering.

#### LUSÍADA UNIVERSITY OF LISBON

MAJOR GRADUATION - COMMUNICATION AND MULTIMEDIA

Lisbon, PT, Graduated of 2012 as finest student of the course

Major graduation oriented for the studies of management, planning and development of design and digital media projects, as well as, in technical part the user experience design, audiovisual production, photography, front-end development, semiotics and perception psychology & visual rhetorics.

#### CACILHAS-TEJO HIGH SCHOOL

UPPER SECONDARY EDUCATION - DIGITAL DESIGN AND MEDIA

Lisbon, PT, Graduated of 2009 as finest student of the course

Upper secondary graduation (level 4 of NQF) includes generic secondary high school study programme, as well as professional specialization on a design, front-end development and digital media.

# **EDUCATION IN MINOR COURSES (CERTIFICATIONS)**

CS50 - HARVARD

DEVELOPMENT - PYTHON AND JAVASCRIPT

Digital, Ongoing since 2021

UDEMY

**PYTHON** 

Digital, Ongoing since 2021

IEFF

CCP - PEDAGOGICAL COMPETENCE CERTIFICATE

Lisbon, PT, Certificate issued in 2020

FINDMORE ACADEMY

EXPERIENCE DESIGN

Lisbon, PT, Certificate issued in 2020

FLAG - ALTA LÓGICA

**JAVASCRIPT** 

Lisbon, PT, Certificate issued in 2018

LUSÍADA UNIVERSITY OF LISBON

MOTION DESIGN AND VFX

Lisbon, PT, Certificate issued in 2012

THE EDGE

3D STUDIO MAX AND VRAY

Lisbon, PT, Certificate issued in 2010

# **SKILLS**

#### **APPLICATION AND PLATFORMS (ALL ADVANCED):**

Code editors - Sublime Text, Atom and VS Code. Adobe - Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects, Audition, Animate.

UX/UI - Principle, Sketch, Figma, inVision. Microsoft Office - Powerpoint, Excel, Word. Video - Finalcut Pro, Premiere, Edius.

3D - 3D Studio Max, vRay. Instructional - Adapt Authoring Tool, Articulate Storyline, Articulate Rise. Web - WordPress.

#### PROGRAMMING / SCRIPTING:

HTML5 (Advanced), CSS3 & sCSS (Advanced), Javascript (Beginner), Python (Beginner)

#### **EXHIBITIONS AND AWARDS**

CINEUPHORIA 2012 FILM FESTIVAL - Award "Top of the Year" for a horror movie "Ajuda-me"
 2013, Lisbon,PT

NOTÍCIAS MAGAZINE - One of the finnest university graduates in Portugal by 2012, according to Notícias Magazine 2012, Lisbon,PT

LUSÍADA UNIVERSITY OF LISBON - Digital Media Exhibition 2012. Lisbon.PT